# SEAN STICKLAND

ICT Technician Turned Full Stack Software Developer

https://www.portfolio.sandcastleink.nz/

https://github.com/sticklandsm

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sean-stickland-aa26461ab/

021829780 • sticklandsm@gmail.com

# **ABOUT ME**

I'm an early-career software developer with 9 years of experience in ICT support. Software development has been a long-standing hobby of mine, and after completing Dev Academy Aotearoa earlier this year, I'm excited to make it my full-time career.

Dev Academy is an intense TypeScript coding bootcamp that aims to simulate a real agile development team. I excelled in my coursework by approaching new concepts and technology with curiosity and quickly emerged as "one of our most advanced students," as described by the lead teacher.

Combining extensive industry experience in the IT world, with my enthusiasm and aptitude for software development, I am an ideal candidate for a development team.

#### **SKILLS & EXPERTISE**

- Proficient in TypeScript, Node.js, React, Redux, Python, HTML, CSS, Tailwind, MySQL.
- Skilled with Git, GitHub, code reviews, and RESTful APIs.
- Have written extensive unit tests using Jest.
- Not afraid of asking questions, admitting when I don't know something, and finding answers on my own, thanks to many years working in IT.
- Have developed automation scripts in Batch, PowerShell, and Azure Process Automation to streamline ICT tasks and increase efficiency.

# **EXPERIENCE**

# Part Time Work and Side Projects | May 2023 - Present

- Have been studying and building side projects while working part time making and maintaining WordPress websites.
- Created Pictophone, a Pictionary/Telephone hybrid game that can be played online. Check it out here: <a href="https://www.pictophone.sandcastleink.nz/">https://www.pictophone.sandcastleink.nz/</a>

**Dev Academy** | Jan 2023 - May 2023 |

#### Student

- Coached and mentored less experienced students.
- Made various projects in React and Express, while also focusing on human skills like providing feedback, collaboration, and working in agile teams.
- Led a team of 5 in creating a restaurant ordering app, where I took responsibility for coding the back-end and helped with much of the front-end. Check it out here: <a href="https://waitless.sandcastleink.nz/table/1/menu">https://waitless.sandcastleink.nz/table/1/menu</a>

#### **Tekne LTD** | Dec 2020 - Dec 2022 |

#### ICT Technician

- Tekne is a significantly smaller company which fostered a greater sense of individual ownership over challenges and a wider spectrum of tasks to tackle.
- Using Azure Process Automation, I automated the offboarding of leaving employees, saving hours a week, and preventing disgruntled employee incidents.
- Developed strong organizational and communication skills needed to effectively schedule and manage the IT needs of several businesses across NZ.
- Collaborated with team members and clients to solve complex IT challenges, which further developed problem-solving skills and built strong relationships.
- Showed the ability to rapidly adapt to new clients, environments, and systems.

# Vista Entertainment | Apr 2019 - Nov 2020 |

ICT Technician

- Stayed up to date with industry trends and best practices to improve system performance and security, effectively managing risks.
- Collaborated with developers to resolve routine hardware and software issues, further developing my technical and problem-solving skills.

# Sony Mobile, Oceania | Feb 2015 - Dec 2018 |

Service Warranty & Training Manager

■ Managed staff training, repairs, refunds, and dealt with tribunal cases against Sony.

# Sony Electronics, Oceania | Oct 2013 - May 2015 |

Customer Support Representative, IT Specialist

Customer facing consumer support for VAIO laptops.

# **EDUCATION**

2023 - Dev Academy Aotearoa

■ Certificate in Applied Software Development

2010 - Auckland University of Technology

■ Certificate in Computer & Mathematical Sciences

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

During my graduation ceremony at Dev Academy, my teacher specifically called out my aptitude for programming and leadership.

#### **PERSONAL**

In my spare time, apart from coding word games, I enjoy playing guitar, trivia shows, karaoke, watching terrible action movies, and seeing indie rock bands. I like teaching, learning and making people laugh.

#### **REFERENCES**

See below from Dev Academy. Others available upon request.

# Level 5, 12 Morgan Street Level 2, 275 Cuba Street Auckland 1011 Wellington 6011

28 July 2023

To Sean's future employers,

Sean attended and successfully completed the Dev Academy Bootcamp at the Auckland campus in 2023.

As a Lead teacher, I taught and worked closely with Sean throughout this time and I regarded him as one of our most advanced students. He applied himself to every challenge and did so with curiosity.

He seemed to have a natural talent for programming and I was always impressed with the quality of his work. He tended to research his approach well and deliver features in a timely manner. He would also consider proper functionality as well as edge-cases. For example, he delivered server-side API code using database returning arrays to improve performance. This was something he discovered himself.

Sean was an ambitious and reliable teammate among his peers and the quality of their final project reflected his influence. This included presentations which he delivered with confidence.

I appreciated his straight-forward communication style, especially when it came to giving and receiving feedback. Lastly, I enjoyed his sometimes twisted sense of humour.

I recommend Sean as a well-rounded, talented developer and wish him success in his career and chosen craft.

Sincerely,

Alex Coaton (Lead Teacher)

devacademy.co.nz

